Molly Nelson

Santa Barbara, CA

(612) 695-2653 MollyKathrynNelson@gmail.com

Analyst

Analyst with over two years of experience in research analysis and writing reports. Four years of ecommerce and retails experience starting a consumer products brand in the wellness sector. Knowledge of SQL, Excel, and a basic understanding of how the web works. Strong interest in driving business decisions through data-driven insights.

Skills include

- Communication
- Writing
- Microsoft Excel
- Analysis

- eCommerce
- Website Analytics
- SQL
- Intrapersonal skills
- Writing reports
- Digital Analytics
- Teamwork
- Leadership

Experience

Sagient Research, San Diego, CA (remote)
Research Analyst II

Research Analyst

April 2018 - Present February 2016 - March 2018

Hired to perform market research to create Meddevicetracker, a database for medtech business intelligence and investment purposes. Currently focused on collecting data and tracking events to maintain a real-time database and provide data analysis for clients.

- Leads a team of 4 analysts, trains new hires
- Writes reports on medical conferences, quarterly outlooks, and market-moving events
- Collaborates with cross functional teams to determine priority content areas

Paradis Basics, San Francisco, CA

Co-Founder, Digital Analyst

April 2014 - January 2018

Developed original formulas for non-toxic skin-care products that were sold in retailers throughout the U.S. and featured in publications such as People Magazine, Hamptons Magazine, and Byrdie Beauty (Clique Media Group).

- Managed product development and quality control
- Oversaw retail process, including inventory flow, margin profitability, and sales
- Headed ecommerce and sales analytics
- Assisted co-founder with design, branding, marketing, photography

University of San Francisco, San Francisco, CA

Research Assistant, Biology Department

May 2014 - May 2015

Engaged in parasitology research and conducted an independent research project investigating the link between climate change and *Schistosoma mansoni* parasitic infections. Applied the scientific method to design and lead an experiment, collect data, and analyze results in preparation for publication.

- First authored a paper published in the Journal of Invertebrate Pathology
- Created a poster and presented research at USF's Creative & Academic Research Day
- Demonstrated research techniques such as handling parasites, microdissection, microscopy, and histology

Achievements

Published a peer-reviewed paper as an undergraduate student
Publishing market analysis reports as a Research Analyst
Performed physician assistant duties for orthopedic surgeries while volunteering in Honduras
Division I Gold Medalist on the Women's rowing team

Education

University of San Francisco; San Francisco, CA **B.S. Biology** and **English Literature** December 2014 - **3.6/4.0**